Today in this video you will learn
how you can get your two wheeler insured from Amazon.
This video will
not be limited to just the insurance process, it will
also clear all your doubts like how to make a claim,
what is IDB value, what is
comprehensive insurance,
what is third party insurance, which
insurance will be right for you. Sir, I am going to do
some of it in one video, so
please do like the video. Suit
guest track to the audio. So for this you will
open Amazon app, as you open the app,
you have to go to the Amazon Pay area,
just come down a little, then you will
see an option of insurance, in
which you will get the option of bike insurance,
you have to click there, as you
click on bike insurance, first of all
your vehicle number will be asked here, if
you have a scooter or any bike, then
you will just
fill in the bike number here, as we
fill in the number here, so we have
filed up the number, after that you will get an option below,
you have to click on view plan, first of all your bike
number has been entered here, your
registration date  You will be asked on which
date you had registered this vehicle
i.e. purchased it, so whatever
date is there, you will select it here,
after that whatever model number of your vehicle will be there,
it will be automatically searched here using your number,
like if we
want to insure our scooter here now, then
our Honda Activa is 125cc, so it has been
automatically entered here, whatever it is of yours will be entered
here, you can confirm it here,
if it is not fetching, then
you can also search here and select that vehicle
here, as you select,
in the next interface you will be asked
whether your current policy is running, has it expired or is it still continuing,
if it has expired then
you have to click on yes here
and if it is not expired then you have to
click on no here, in the next interface
you will be asked one more question that have you taken
any claim on it in the previous year,
if you have taken a claim then you have to click on yes
and if you have  If you have
not made any claim for your insurance last year,
then you will just click on no and
proceed further here, so what we have now is
that our policy has expired, so
here we will click on gas and
click on confirm here, so
you click on confirm here,
here the details will be opened, I will
explain it one by one properly
so that none of your dots should be there
because insurance is such a sector in
which first of all we have to take care
that we will do the insurance online,
but brother, if our bike meets with an accident, then
how will we claim it,
what is the process of doing it, will
we put it here with Amazon
that brother, make our insurance claim or
where do we have to do it, we will
clear your dot here properly, so
in this interface, first of all you
get to see an option by id value in
which you can see that here it is 22000,
29000, 15000, so after all what is the ID
value  So see, A value
means that if you make an insurance
claim, then the maximum amount that an
insurance company will offer you here is the
IDBI value. Let us
understand it as an example, like here it is 15700, so
if I select IDBI value as 15700 and then do the
insurance further, then the maximum
benefit that the insurance company will give me here is 15700 only. If I
select 22429 and proceed further, then the maximum
benefit that the insurance company will give me is 22429 only. In what time will the benefit be
given here? Similarly, 29000 has also been done here,
so you decide here,
if you select a higher IDBI value, then
you will have to pay a higher premium
and if you select a slightly lower IDBI value, then
you will have to pay a slightly lower premium.
So I think
you must have understood the concept of IDBI value, then
you will
get two options for insurance in Amazon, the
first option is comprehensive plan and the
second is third party.  Plane: So, which
plan do you have to choose here, I will
tell you here. As many people
know what happens between comprehensive and third party, then you can
script the video, you can see the next step,
but I am explaining to you
which plan would be better for you.
See, what happens in comprehensive plan,
comprehensive means that there will be on-
damage tax and third party will also be included,
this means that if your car meets with an
accident, then if you take an insurance,
whatever is the insurance of your car, that tax will definitely be there,
along with that third party
insurance is also included in it,
but if you do
not want to take comprehensive plan and only
want to take third party plan, then what will happen in it is that there will be
no on-damage tax of your car,
this means that if your car meets with an accident, then if there is
any damage, then
that insurance company will
not repair your car, you are not going to get any claim for it,
so third part or
we will take it, so third party is a
mandatory insurance, this means
If you are taking your vehicle on the road, then the
government rule is that your
vehicle should have at least third party
insurance, otherwise you will be immediately
challaned here. So,
if you just want to save yourself from the challan, then you
can definitely go with third party insurance.
You will also be
charged a little less insurance premium here, but if you
want that the damage to your vehicle is also covered here, then
you should
also go with comprehensive plan, the cost of which has been
mentioned here. Now see,
if you take comprehensive plan, then
what taxes will be there in it and what taxes will not be there. It is
very important for you to know that for which
things you will get claim and for which things you will
not get claim. Okay,
before telling this, let me tell you one thing, see here the
comprehensive plan is being told as ₹875 for
one year with GST and for third party
plan it is being told as ₹714 with
GST. Now, here I would like to suggest you one thing, I would
personally like to suggest you that
see what is there right now,  As far as
I have seen, Amazon
provides you insurance with Aqua. Aqua is
a good company, a very big company which
provides you insurance, so if
you do insurance with Amazon now, you will get
insurance, but I have seen this thing by
comparing that if you do
insurance directly with X, then
you will see a huge difference in the price of Amazon and X, so
I would recommend you
not to get insurance from Amazon right now because this
direct will take you to the story, I am
showing you the proof here because
Amazon provides you insurance with X, so you should do
this with Aqua only,
I will
show you here as live proof that
you will get
more benefit by doing it directly with Aqua. Compare it to
Amazon, so what will you have to do for this,
I have given you the link in the description of the video, if you
click on it, then you will
directly come to this type of interface,
this is another official website here,
because if you do it directly, then you will
definitely get some 100-200 rupees back.
I am telling you this for your profitable deal,
otherwise you can do it from Amazon itself, it will cost 100
rupees more, I will also show you by comparing,
okay, so you just
click on the link here, I have given it in the description,
after this you will have to enter your bike
number here, so let's
enter our bike number here, after that we will
proceed here, as you proceed here,
first of all you will have to
tell your model number, as you just
saw, we filed up the details in Amazon,
you will file up the details in the same way, as you
file up the details here,
you will get two options in this way, comprehensive
plan and third party plan, as
I was also showing you Amazon here,
now see how the difference will be here, it is
showing 846, 22000 ID value
in Aqua directly and if you are doing it from Amazon, then
see, it was showing ₹940 for 22 thousand, that's why
I told you
not to do it direct because you will get
more benefit in Aqua  It is possible that
Amazon might have kept some commission here,
I don't know, but I am showing the comparison
that if you do it from Amazon also, then
you will have to pay a little more here,
okay, so let me go to the mother, if
you are doing
insurance directly from Amazon here, then you are here, further
after that I am showing you the process of
how to do the insurance,
I will tell you everything about the rest of the claim etc., how to do it there,
stay tension free, okay, so
first of all you have to contact here,
for how many years do you want to take the insurance, there is an option of
1 year, there is an option of 2 years, there is a 3
year, so select as per your
convenience, in three years you will
save something here, 123 will be the
serving of Rs. 61 in two years, so
if you are buying only from third party, then
definitely do it for 3 years, definitely
doing it once will be a good
saving for you, okay, so we will
show you by doing only one year here, let's start with Prism,
you can buy comprehensive,  It
means you will also have to pay tax on damage to your vehicle.
Now see what all taxes are there here
in a comprehensive plan.
First of all, accident tax will be there
if you have a car accident, then
definitely any damage to the car will be taxed. If
anything gets
damaged in your car through fire, that will also be
taxed. If there is a theft, that is, if
your car gets stolen, then that will also be taxed here.
Claim means if there is an
earthquake here, anything damaged due to it,
that will also be taxed here.
Third party injury means if you
hit someone, then if he dies, then that
also becomes taxed here. And
third party property means if you hit
someone and whatever
damage is done to his bike, that also becomes taxed here
in comprehensive plan. What tax is
not there, non-accidental damage, if there is no
damage due to an accident, then
that will not be claimed in the insurance.
Illegal driving, if you  If you are drunk and driving, if you are
driving after consuming any alcohol, if you are doing
anything then that is
not taxable here. Okay, so I have
told you this, if you take a comprehensive plan then what will be the tax
and what will not be the tax,
for which you will have to pay Rs. 846 per year here,
it depends on the bike,
if your bike is more expensive then
you will have to pay the
tax accordingly here, if you only
want to take a third party plan, that means you just
want to save yourself from the challan, then what is the tax in it, what is the tax in it,
what will happen in the third party, if you
hit someone and he dies, then that will be taxed,
if you
hit someone, then whatever damage is done to their bike will be
taxed, will there not be any tax on the bike, that means
any damage happens to your bike, I am telling you clearly, if there is any
damage to your bike
in an accident, then that will not be taxed in the third party,
okay,
if you are doing all this after consuming alcohol then
that is not taxed here
now  There is a slight price difference between third party and comprehensive,
which
you can also see here on the top of the screen,
okay, so here I will show
you third party insurance as a live proof,
because if I do comprehensive then you have to
take a photo of the bike there and
upload it, okay, so I am
doing third party, otherwise you
can also take comprehensive here, so
I have selected third party here,
just click on continue here,
as you click on continue here, there is an
add here,
you can take this add if you want or you can not, otherwise
you will have to pay Rs 350 extra
here, so you can add it if you want,
otherwise you just have to
click on continue here, as you click on
continue, you have to
file up the basic details here because
whatever insurance certificate comes, it will be
provided to you in this detail, so it is
necessary for you to keep the physical certificate in the bike, okay, here you will file up the name, you will
file up the email ID, your
mobile number will be automatically filled, your P
code  Whatever is there here, we will file it up.
If you have GST number, it is optional.
If you want, you can also add it, otherwise we will
not add it. Okay, then just fill it up. So,
here we have filed up the details and
just click on continue.
Like, here you have bike number,
model number, registration is updated. The
ID value is showing here. It was
telling here when your policy will start. Whether it is third party or own damage, it is
shown here.
Here a final amount will come,
premium is 714, 18%. GST will be levied here
of 129. So, you will have to pay this GST.
So, total, our 1
year third party insurance of my
scooter will be done here for
₹843. So, the insurance has to be done here for ₹843.
Just click on Pino here. As we
click on Pino,
you will get multiple options for making payment here.
Debit card, credit card, whatever is there above,
you will select it here and make the payment.
Here we have made the payment through PhonePe.  It is
given that as you make the payment, you
can do it through any payment method, credit
card, debit card, you will get the sir option,
so here you can see that it is
said here that your payment has been completed here,
now here you will have to complete
KYC, after that your policy will be
activated here, so what
is here, for KYC you will find 'Start'
written below, you just have to
click here, as you click here, then in
online insurance
you will have to give proof in insurance, only then
your policy will be
activated here, so here you can enter the PAN
card number in the address group, driving
license, Aadhar card, water ID card,
passport or DG Locker's issue,
you can complete the KYC here,
so click on Start KYC,
first of all you will enter your full name here, which
we have filled the name here, just
click on Continue, as you
click on Continue, the PAN card
number, then you will have to file up the date of birth here, the
PAN card
number and date of birth have been filed up here,
click on Proceed  As you
click on proceed here, a little
time is taken here, after that you will have to do
document verification, so you
can get the document verification done in two ways, upload document i.e. by
uploading the photo by clicking here or if
you have Digi Locker then you will be
able to update it here near DigiLocker, so
what to do in just upload document,
if you want to upload Aadhar card then
click on Aadhar card, otherwise you have to upload a photo of driving
license, water card or passport, whatever
you have, just by clicking on it,
Aadhar card will be best, you
click on Aadhar card, click on capture photo,
your camera will open, you will
click on the photo of Aadhar card here, everyone has captured the photo of Aadhar card here,
as you click here your photo gets
uploaded here, the
back side of the Aadhar card will also have to be captured here, so
just you click on capture photo, the
camera will open, the back side of the Aadhar card will be
clicked and
uploaded here, so let us click, so
as you upload the photo
Your KYC gets completed here,
as soon as your KYC is complete, it will be
written here that your policy
document will be ready and provided to you in two to three minutes,
but it does not take even two to three minutes,
your policy receipt gets
created instantly here, so for this
you will get the option below, by creating your
account, you will click here, as
you click here, all your
insurances running with you are
shown here, as I have already got
all of mine insured with you, so just
now we have insured Honda
Activa in front of you here, so right
now the insurance will
not be activated instantly, today's date is 18th July
2021 and your insurance will be activated on
21st July 2013, that is, it takes two-three days for the
insurance to get activated,
but the PF, which is the insurance paper, will be
available to you instantly,
what you have to do for this, you just have to
select your bike here, as
you do here  But you will select it, whatever your
details are, they are uploaded here, here
you will find a download written,
you just have to click here, PF download,
click here, as you
download the PF, a PF is downloaded in your mobile phone number
and here is your
insurance paper, just take a printout of it and
keep it in your vehicle,
no challan will be taken from you here.
Sir, the first thing mentioned here is
when is your policy starting, when did you do it,
how much amount did you do it, your vehicle
number, registration date, all this is
mentioned here, which you normally get done offline also, whether it is
ICC
Lombard or Bajaj, you get
to see only this paper of insurance, so
you will get this same paper PF with the car, get
it printed out,
keep the physical copy in your bike definitely and in
this way you
can get your bike insured sitting at home, which
I have shown you with live proof, I have even
made and shown you the insurance paper here, so in
this way your
bike will be insured here, now first of all  The big
question that will arise here is that
we have taken insurance, so how? If we have to make a claim, then
what is the process here? First of all,
you have to wait for the insurance to be activated, it takes
3 days, only
after that your claim will be processed, then
you will get two options, first of all this is the toll
free number, I am telling you the most solid method, there is
a toll free number of Eco, you just call
here, after calling, you have to
say that you want to make an insurance claim of
your vehicle, you will just be asked for the policy number
which is mentioned here in your PF,
you will tell the policy number or the vehicle
number, they will take out the sir details, as soon as
your sir details reach them,
you will tell that this is what has happened in your vehicle,
you want to make an insurance claim, so it is
online, so there will not be much physical
verification of you, what
happened, what did not happen, you may be
asked for photos etc., but sir, through the
online process, your
claim will be processed online here and whatever
your settlement is, whatever happens,
your claim will be made here in the proper manner, so
very  It is a free process
because I have definitely insured my bike here many times,
so I have not faced any problem till now,
so you can also make a claim in this way,
this is the first method, a very solid
method, I told you, the second method is that
just next to the interface of my account,
you
get the option of making a claim, you can also register your claim here by
clicking on claim against the issue of your App,
but in the last option, if you have to
come tomorrow then you can do it directly in customer care
tomorrow, that is the best option,
I have told you here,
I have not seen any such problem till now, it is a
very big company, it is a well-
known company, you must have definitely seen Eco's insurance
in many big platforms,
which will be your
Oyo, it is available in many places,
you will buy your mobile phone on Amazon itself, so it
is a good company, definitely Amazon
prefers it, okay, so
here I have given you live proof  If you have
shown insurance with this then
please like the video and
share it so that everyone comes to
know that it is not necessary that you have to get the
insurance done from your showroom only,
you can save money by getting
insurance done online and your money will be back to a great extent,
I have compared it many times and seen
that the insurance which is done online for ₹800-900, is
taken from you at the showroom for ₹14-1500 by
adding unnecessary charges here, so
you can definitely get your bike's insurance done online sitting at home
and if you want to get your car's
insurance done as well then  We have
already made a video on this, so
you can download this video by clicking here, so we will
meet together, till now
Jai Hind Jai Bharat.